Guide to the Samuel J. Tilden papers, 1794-1886 [bulk 1835-1876]
The New York Public Library. Manuscripts and Archives Division.
- Series I. Correspondence, 1810 - 1919, n.d.; 38247; 35 boxes, 14.5 linear feet
  - I. B. General, 1830 - 1919, n.d.; 38280
    - Trevor, John Bond, 1876 - 1886; 39495 (Box 24, Folder 59)
      Also includes letters from Trevor's wife, Emily.
    - Trinity Church, 1846; 39496 (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - Troy House, 1846; 39497 (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - Trumbull, Lyman, 1884; 39498 (Box 24, Folder 62)
    - Tucker, Gideon J., 1866; 39499 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Tucker, J. R., 1877; 39500 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Tucker, P., 1846; 39501 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Tuncliffe, George E., 1875 - 1876; 39502 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Turnure, Arthur B., 1884; 39503 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Turrill, G., 1856; 39504 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Tuttle, George F., 1883; 39505 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Tweed, William Marcy, 1866 - 1868; 39506 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Tyler, Nathaniel, undated; 39507 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Uhl, Hermann, 1875 - 1876; 39508 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Underhill, E. F., ca. 1865; 39509 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Union League Club, 1871; 39510 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Upson, William Henry., 1868; 39511 (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - Usher, J.P., 1860 - 1863; 39512 (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Vache, Alexander F., 1846; 39513 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Vail, M. Bedell {1886}0., 39514 (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Valentine, D. T., 1843, 1846; 39515 (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Vallandingham, Clement Laird, 1868; 39516 (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Van Allen, John J., 1875; 39517 (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Van Buren, Abraham, 1832, 1858 - 1861; 39518 (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Van Buren, John, 1848 - 1876, n.d.; 39519 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Van Buren, Martin, 1842 - 1867; 39520 (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Van Buren, Myndert, 1868; 39521 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Van Buren, William, 1875; 39522 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Van Cott, Joshua M., 1872, 1875; 39523 (Box 25, Folder 25)
    - Vanderbilt, Cornelius, 1872; 39524 (Box 25, Folder 26)
    - Vanderbilt, William Henry, 1874, 1882; 39525 (Box 25, Folder 27)
    - Vanderpoel, Aaron, 1832 - 1846; 39526 (Box 25, Folder 28)
    - Vanderpoel, Aaron J., 1876 - 1878, 1881; 39527 (Box 25, Folder 29)
    - Van Dyke, James C., 1864; 39528 (Box 25, Folder 30)
    - Van Hoesen, George M., 1876; 39529 (Box 25, Folder 31)
    - Van Ness, Jesse, 1839; 39530 (Box 25, Folder 32)
    - Van Schaick, J., 1876; 39531 (Box 25, Folder 33)
    - Varian, Joshua M., 1875; 39532 (Box 25, Folder 34)
    - Varnum, James M., 1863, 1865, 1876; 39533 (Box 25, Folder 35)
    - Vaughn, Virginia, 1882; 39534 (Box 25, Folder 36)
    - Vaux, Calvert, 1881; 39535 (Box 25, Folder 37)
    - Vaux, Richard, 1868 - 1871, 1875; 39536 (Box 25, Folder 38)
    - Vest, George G., 1879, 1884; 39537 (Box 25, Folder 39)
    - Vilas, William M., 1885; 39538 (Box 25, Folder 40)
    - Voorhees, D. W., 1866; 39539 (Box 25, Folder 41)
    - Wachner, L.C., 1875; 39540 (Box 25, Folder 42)
    - Waite, M. R., 1866, 1881; 39541 (Box 25, Folder 43)
    - Wakeman, George, 1869; 39542 (Box 25, Folder 44)
    - Wakeman, T. B., 1846; 39543 (Box 25, Folder 45)
    - Waldo, A. B., 1872; 39544 (Box 25, Folder 46)
    - Walker, George, 1876; 39545 (Box 25, Folder 47)
    - Walker, Henry, 1880; 39546 (Box 25, Folder 48)
    - Walker, Mary Edwards, 1878, 1881; 39547 (Box 25, Folder 49)
    - Walker, Robert, 1868; 39548 (Box 25, Folder 50)
    - Wallace, Robert, 1877; 39549 (Box 25, Folder 51)
    - Wallace, William A., 1866 - 1871; 39550 (Box 25, Folder 52)
    - Walson, Thomas H., 1884 - 1886; 39551 (Box 25, Folder 53)
    - Ward, C. L., 1868; 39552 (Box 25, Folder 54)
    - Ward, Samuel Cutler, 1868 -1879; 39553 (Box 25, Folder 55)
    - Ward, Townsend, 1860; 39554 (Box 25, Folder 56)
    - Warner, Andrew, 1843; 39555 (Box 25, Folder 57)
    - Warner, Joseph, 1875; 39556 (Box 25, Folder 58)
    - Warner, S., 1875; 39557 (Box 25, Folder 59)
    - Waterbury, Nelson J., 1841 - 1885, n.d.; 39558 (Box 25, Folder 60-61)
    - Watterson, Henry, 1872 - 1885, n.d.; 39559 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Wayland, Francis, 1875 - 1876; 39560 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Weaver, E. M., 1882; 39561 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Webb, William H., 1868, 1876, n.d; 39562 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Webster, Sidney, 1852 - 1876, 1885; 39563 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Weed, Smith M., 39564
      - 1866 - 1876, 292075 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - 1877 - 1879, 292076 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - 1880 - 1881, 292077 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - 1882 - 1883, 292078 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - 1884 - 1885, 292079 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - undated, 292080 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Weed, Thurlow, 1832; 39565 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Weir, George, 1858; 39566 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Welles, Gideon, 1844 - 1876; 39567 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Wells, David A., 1872 - 1876, 1885; 39568 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Wendell, C., 1868; 39569 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - West, David, 1832 - 1845, n.d.; 39570 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - West, Dewitt C., 1872; 39571 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - West, Jesse, 1846; 39572 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Westbrook, Theodoric R., 1875 - 1876; 39573 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Western, H.M., 1846; 39574 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Weston, Edward Payson, 1885; 39575 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Wetmore, Prosper Montgomery, 1846, 1848; 39576 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Wetmore, W. L., 1864 - 1876; 39577 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Wheaton, Charles, 1868; 39578 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Wheaton, Horace, 1848; 39579 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Wheeler, Charles C., 1879; 39580 (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Wheeler, D.E., 1876; 39581 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Wheeler, J. D., 1846; 39582 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - White, B., 1868; 39583 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - White, Andrew Dickinson, 1874 - 1875; 39584 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - White, Horace, 1874 - 1875, 1885; 39585 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - White, Peter, 1876, 1885; 39586 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - White, Philo, 1870, 1875; 39587 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - White, William Pinkney, 1874 - 1876; 39588 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Whitehead, D., 1865; 39589 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Whitney, Charles A., 1844; 39590 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Whitney, James S., 1864, 1870, 1876; 39591 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Whitney, William C., 1871 - 1885; 39592 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - Wickham, William H., 1872 - 1879; 39593 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Wilkinson, Alfred, 1872, 1875; 39594 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Wilkinson, John, 1862, 1873; 39595 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Willers, Diedrich Jr., 1874; 39596 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Williams, J. L., 1865; 39597 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Willson, H.P., 1870; 39598 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Wilson, J., 1848; 39599 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Wilson, James Grant, 1885; 39600 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Wilson, Matthew, 1881; 39601 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Wilson, R. L., 1884; 39602 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Wilmer, Joseph P., 1846; 39603 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Winfield, Charles H., 1866 - 1875, n.d.; 39604 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Wingate, George W., 1875; 39605 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Winslow, R., 1846; 39606 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Winslow, Lanier & Company, 1874 - 1884; 39607 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Wittenburg, T. C., 1859; 39608 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Wood, Benjamin R., 1871, 1875, 1880; 39609 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Wood, Fernando, 1859 - 1878, n.d.; 39610 (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Woodbury, Charles H., 1876; 39611 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Woodford, Stewart L., 1875 - 1876; 39612 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Woodward, James Otis, 1886; 39613 (Box 27, Folder 22)
    - Woodward, John B., 1876, 1879; 39614 (Box 27, Folder 23)
    - Worcester, E.D., 1865; 39615 (Box 27, Folder 24)
    - Workingmen's Democratic Republican Association, 1864; 39616 (Box 27, Folder 25)
    - Wright, Horatio, 1868 - 1870; 39617 (Box 27, Folder 26)
    - Wright, Silas, 1838 - 1846, 1877, n.d; 39618 (Box 27, Folder 27)
    - Wright, William B., 1880; 39619 (Box 27, Folder 28)
    - Yale University, 1875; 39620 (Box 27, Folder 29)
    - Yard, W. Sterling, undated; 39621 (Box 27, Folder 30)
    - Youmans, Edward Birdsall, 1875, 1886; 39622 (Box 27, Folder 31)
    - Young, James R., 1864 - 1867; 39623 (Box 27, Folder 32)
    - Young, Thomas, 1856; 39624 (Box 27, Folder 33)
    - Young Men's Democratic Union Club, 1876, 1880; 39625 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Zborowski, Marton, 1875; 39626 (Box 27, Folder 36)
    - Unidentified, 1828 - 1888, undated; 39627 (Box 27, Folder 36-37)
  - I. C. Counsel of the Corporation, 1843 - 1844, n.d.; 39628 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    One folder of letters sent and received by Tilden in his official capacity as Corporate Counsel for the City of New York. Most letters relate to requests for political appointments, including letters of reference and recommendation for potential appointees. Additional records relating to the Counsel of the Corporation may be found in Series II.
  - I. D. Tweed Ring, 1870 - 1872 March; 39629
    Correspondence relating to the Tweed Ring consists mainly of letters and telegrams between Tilden, his compatriots, and bank officers involved in the investigation of the Tweed Ring's accounting practices, as well as communications with some of the individuals charged with malfeasance. Notable correspondents include A. Oakey Hall, Henry A. Richmond, Allen C. Beach, John Van Buren, William F. Havermeyer, and Charles O'Conor. Additional material relating to the Tweed Ring may be found in Series VI.
    - 1870 Jun-1871 Oct, 292037 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - 1871 Nov-Dec and undated, 292038 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - 1872 Jan-Feb, 292039 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - 1872 Mar, 292040 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - 1872 Apr-1873 Dec, 292041 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - 1874-1875, 292042 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - 1876-1877, 292043 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - I. E. New York State Assembly, 1867 - 1872; 39630
    Correspondence relating to Tilden's activities as a member of the State Legislature, particularly the impeachment of New York State Supreme Court Justices George G. Barnard, Albert Cardozo, and John McCunn; and an investigation into allegations of fraud within the Fire Commission. Additional material relating to the New York State Assembly may be found in Series VII.
    - Fire commissioners investigation, 1872 - 1876; 39631 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Judicial misconduct, 1872; 39632 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - I. F. Gubernatorial, 1874 - 1876; 39633
    Gubernatorial Correspondence falls into three categories: correspondence relating to the exposure and disbandment of the Canal Ring; Constituent letters; and letters relating to legislation proposed during Tilden's term in office. Canal ring correspondence covers appointments to the Canal Investigating Commission, and letters discussing the discovery and prosecution of fraud within the state canal system. Proposed legislation is arranged by topic, and includes correspondence regarding bills proposed in the areas of prisons and asylums, city assessments, charter reform, education, emigration, public works, and railways and transportation. Also included is a file of letters received by Tilden from prison inmates or their families requesting pardons. Constituent letters from the public at large comprise the largest portion of the Gubernatorial Correspondence, and range from requests for pictures and autographs to letters of support and encouragement during the 1876 election, with occasional offers of physical violence or civil disobedience on his behalf. Additional material relating to Tilden's time in office may be found in Series VIII.
    - Canal Ring, 1867 - 1878, n.d.; 39634 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Canal Ring, 1867 - 1878, n.d.; 39635 (Box 29, Folder 1-5)
    - Constituent letters, 1875 - 1876 Nov; 39636 (Box 29, Folder 6-13)
    - Constituent letters, 1876 Nov - 1878; 39637 (Box 30, Folder 1-11)
    - Constituent letters, 1879 - 1886; 39638 (Box 31, Folder 1-5)
    - Proposed legislation, 1874 - 1876; 39639
      - General legislative correspondence, 1874 - 1876; 39640 (Box 31, Folder 6-11)
      - Adulterated milk bill, 1875 May - Jun; 39641 (Box 32, Folder 1)
      - Asylums, 1874 Dec - 1876 Apr; 39642 (Box 32, Folder 2)
      - Binghampton Inebriate Asylum, 1876 Jan - Feb; 39643 (Box 32, Folder 3)
      - Brooklyn assessment bills, 1875 Apr - Jun; 39644 (Box 32, Folder 4)
      - Buffalo reassessment bill, 1875 Apr - May; 39645 (Box 32, Folder 5)
      - Charter reform, 1875 Dec - 1876 Feb; 39646 (Box 32, Folder 6)
      - Clinton County fisheries, 1875 May - Jun; 39647 (Box 32, Folder 7)
      - Court session efficiency bill, 1875 Apr - May; 39648 (Box 32, Folder 8)
      - Disbandement of 79th Regiment, 1875 Dec; 39649 (Box 32, Folder 9)
      - Docks, wharves and slips, 1875 Apr - May; 39650 (Box 32, Folder 10)
      - Education, 1875 Apr - Dec; 39651 (Box 32, Folder 11)
      - Emigration, 1874 Nov -Dec; 1875 May - Nov; 39652 (Box 32, Folder 12)
      - Greenpoint ferry bill, 1875 May - Jun; 39653 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Greenwich Elevated Railroad, 1874 Oct, 1875 Feb - May; 39654 (Box 32, Folder 14)
      - Hay bailing bill, 1875 Mar - Apr; 39655 (Box 32, Folder 15)
      - Insurance, 1875 May - Nov; 39656 (Box 32, Folder 16)
      - Manhattan Loan & Trust Company, 1875 Jun; 39657 (Box 32, Folder 17)
      - Monroe County treasurer's bill, 1875 May - Jun; 39658 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      - New Brighton dock bill, 1875 May - Jun; 39659 (Box 32, Folder 19)
      - New capitol building, 1875 Jan - May; 39660 (Box 32, Folder 20)
      - New York sheriff's bill, 1875 Jun; 39661 (Box 32, Folder 21)
      - Old Soldiers claims, 1875 Nov - 1876 Mar; 39662 (Box 32, Folder 22)
      - Pardons requested, 1875 - 1876; 39663 (Box 32, Folder 23)
      - Pilotage bill, 1875 May; 39664 (Box 32, Folder 24)
      - Police and Police justices bill, 1875 May - Jun; 39665 (Box 32, Folder 25)
      - Prisons and prison reform, 1874 Nov - 1876 Mar; 39666 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Proposed municipal college in Central Park, 1875 May; 39667 (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - Public works bill, 1875 Feb; 39668 (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Railroads and railway transportation, 1874 - 1876; 39669 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Riverside Avenue bill, 1875 Jan, 1876 May - Jun; 39670 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Rochester charter amendments, 1876 Feb; 39671 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      - Safe deposit bill, 1875 Apr - Jun; 39672 (Box 33, Folder 7)
      - Salt springs, 1875 Apr - Dec; 39673 (Box 33, Folder 8)
      - Seneca Falls charter, 1875 Apr; 39674 (Box 33, Folder 9)
      - Topographical survey, 1875 Dec; 39675 (Box 33, Folder 10)
      - Utica extension, 1875 Feb - May; 39676 (Box 33, Folder 11)
      - Washington Ironworks bill, 1875 Feb - Mar; 39677 (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - West Point bill, 1875 Mar - May; 39678 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - I. G. Subject files, 1841 - 1986 n.d.; 39679
    Includes correspondence with booksellers; a file of political circulars received; and a file of letters relating to coastal defense, though this topic is also covered at length in General Correspondence with John Newton, William Henry Jacques, and Samuel Randall. Also retained are letters from the general public soliciting Tilden's patronage.
    - Booksellers and publishers, 39680
      - Barrie, George, 1880; 39681 (Box 33, Folder 14)
      - Beatty & Stevenson, 1884; 39682 (Box 33, Folder 15)
      - Bibliopole/Henry K. Van Siclen, 1885 - 1886; 39683 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      - Brentano Brothers, 1882 - 1886; 39684 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Cassell, Petter, Galpin & Co., 1882; 39685 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      - The Century Company, 1883; 39686 (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - D. Lothrop & Co., 1886; 39687 (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Estes & Lauriat, 1881 - 1884; 39688 (Box 33, Folder 21)
      - G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1879 - 1885; 39689 (Box 33, Folder 22)
      - Grant, F. E., 1880 - 1884; 39690 (Box 33, Folder 23)
      - J. & G. H. Langley, 1841; 39691 (Box 33, Folder 24)
      - J.W. Bouton Booksellers, 1860 - 1881; 39692 (Box 33, Folder 25-28)
      - Joel Munsell's Sons, 1885 - 1886; 39693 (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Little, Brown & Co., 39694 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Littlefield, George E., 1884; 39695 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - R. Worthington Publishers, 1884, 1886; 39696 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      - Scribner & Welford/Scribner's Sons, 1877, 1882 - 1886; 39697 (Box 34, Folder 5)
      - Smith, Mrs. G. C., 1886; 39698 (Box 34, Folder 6)
      - Van Nostrand, D., 1886; 39699 (Box 34, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous booksellers and publishers, 1876 - 1886; 39700 (Box 34, Folder 8-10)
    - Calling cards, undated; 39701 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Canals, 1874 - 1876; 39702 (Box 34, Folder 12-14)
    - Circulars received, 1840 - 1885; n.d.; 39703 (Box 34, Folder 15-17)
    - Coastal defense, 1885 - 1886; 39704 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Genealogical research, 1852 - 1886; 39705 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Greystone Jersey cattle, 1879 - 1882; 39706 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Railroads, 39707
      - Chicago & Great Northern Railway, 1885; 39708 (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Chicago & Great Western Railway, 1865; 39709 (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Illinois Central Railroad Co., 1874; 39710 (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Metropolitan Railway, 1875; 39711 (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Montclair & Greenwood Lake Railway Co., 1878; 39712 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Solicitation letters, 1854 - 1886, n.d.; 39713 (Box 35, Folder 9-11)
- Series II. Counsel of the Corporation, 1839 - 1844, n.d.; 39714; 3 boxes, 2 volumes; 1.5 linear feet
  Tilden was appointed Corporation Counsel for the city of New York in 1843, though he was removed in 1844 when Mayor James Harper took office.
  Documentation of the office of Corporation Counsel for the City of New York includes fines for violations of city ordinances; complaints lodged against individuals charged with weighing articles without a weighmaster's appointment; lists of summonses returnable to various judges; subpoenas; and registers of monies received by Tilden on behalf of the Corporation Counsel. Additional records relating to the Counsel of the Corporation may be found in Series I.
  - Legal documents and receipts, 1839 - 1843; 39715 (Box 35, Folder 12-13)
  - Legal documents and receipts, 1843 - 1844, n.d.; 39716 (Box 36, Folder 1-8)
  - Log of judgments obtained, 1843 - 1844; 39717 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Cash book, 1843 - 1844; 39718 (Volume 3)
  - Complaint book, 1843 - 1844; 39719 (Volume 4)
- Series III. Legal Files, 1832 - 1891, n.d.; 39720; 20 boxes, 3 volumes; 8.6 linear feet
  In the 1850s and 1860s, Tilden left politics to focus on his legal career and became a celebrated corporate lawyer, often serving as counsel for major railroads and coal companies.
  The Legal series is comprised mainly of case files, transcripts of testimonies, drafts of Tilden's arguments, and other administrative documents relating to his cases. Material covering various corporate cases is also present, demonstrating not only Tilden's expertise in the area of corporate law, but his personal interest in the industries through which he made his personal fortune. Material is arranged chronologically by case.
  - III. A. Delaware & Hudson Canal Company vs. Pennsylvania Coal Company, 1832 - 1864; 39721
    In a breach of contract suit brought by the Delaware & Hudson Canal Company against the Pennsylvania Coal Company, Tilden represented the defendant, and secured a victory through analysis of statistics proving that enlarged canals increased, rather than decreased, the time and expenses incurred by the coal company in transporting their goods.
    Includes correspondence; case files containing figures, statistics, historical documentation of both companies involved in the suit, and legal documents generated over the course of the case; arguments from defense counsel; notes and drafts relating to Tilden's arguments; and printed reports from the canal and coal companies.
    - Correspondence, 1846 - 1863, n.d.; 39722 (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
    - Case files, ca. 1850s - 1860s; 39723 (Box 37, Folder 3-6)
    - Case files, ca. 1850s - 1860s; 39724 (Box 38, Folder 1-6)
    - Case files, ca. 1850s - 1860s; 39725 (Box 39, Folder 1-4)
    - Arguments, 1863, n.d.; 39726 (Box 39, Folder 5-10)
    - Arguments, 1863, n.d.; 39727 (Box 40, Folder 1-8)
    - Arguments, 1863, n.d.; 39728 (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
    - Draft material, 1863; 39729 (Box 41, Folder 4-7)
    - Printed material, 1832 - 1864, n.d.; 39730 (Box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - III. B. Cumberland Coal & Iron Company vs. Sherman, Dean & Postley{1840 - 1863, n.d.}, 39731
    Tilden represented the Cumberland Coal & Iron Company when it brought suit against members of its board. The suit claimed the board had authorized Allen M. Sherman, company president, to sell a large portion of its mining lands at an undervalued price to a holding company in which Sherman, along with board members William B. Dean and S.B. Postley, held a significant financial interest.
    Consists of correspondence; drafts of Tilden's points for the plaintiff and related notes, research on legal precedents and related court decisions; case files containing copies of the complaint, summonses, affidavits, plaintiff's evidence, and other material supporting their complaint; copies of testimony; and printed reports from the Cumberland Coal & Iron Company.
    - Correspondence, 1858 - 1863, ND; 39732 (Box 42, Folder 4-10)
    - Case Files, 1846 - 1863, n.d.; 39733 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Case Files, 1846 - 1863, n.d.; 39734 (Box 43, Folder 1-6)
    - Case Files, 1846 - 1863, n.d.; 39735 (Box 44, Folder 1-9)
    - Testimony, 1854 - 1859, 1861; 39736
      - 1854 - 1856, 39737 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      - 1859, 39738 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      - 1861, 39739 (Box 45, Folder 3-5)
      - Undated, 39740 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Closing arguments, 1858; 39741 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Notes and drafts, undated; 39742 (Box 46, Folder 1-6)
    - Printed material, 1852 - 1858; 39743 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - III. C. Giles-Flagg contested election, 1855 - 1856; 39744
    In 1855, the Know-Nothing party ran an obscure candidate for State Comptroller against Democratic Party stalwart Azariah C. Flagg. Flagg won by a slim majority, but the Know-Nothings contested that a clerical error in the Nineteenth Ward had resulted in 316 voted being credited to Flagg which should have been credited to Giles, and presented a number of witnesses who gave testimony to that fact. Many of the original vote tallies had been conveniently "lost." Tilden analyzed the available figures and reconstructed the missing tallies, disproving the contestant's theory that votes from the Nineteenth Ward had been transposed.
    Case files include transcripts of testimony, reconstructed vote tallies, drafts of Tilden's remarks, and other relevant documents.
    - Case files, 1855 - 1856; 39745 (Box 47, Folder 1-5)
  - III. D. Cunningham-Burdell murder case, 1857, n.d.; 39746
    In 1857, Emma Augusta Cunningham was tried and acquitted for the murder of her lodger, Dr. Harvey Burdell. Following the murder trial, Tilden successfully represented Burdell's family when Mrs. Cunningham brought suit against Burdell's family, claiming that they had been secretly married, and that she was owed a widow's share of his estate.
    Includes correspondence, transcripts of testimony, memoranda and exhibits relating to the trial, as well as research and evidence compiled by Tilden to demonstrate contradictions in the testimony of Cunningham's daughter, Augusta.
    - Correspondence, 1857; 39747 (Box 47, Folder 6-8)
    - Testimony, 1857; 39748 (Box 48, Folder 1-9)
    - Testimony, 1857; 39749 (Box 49, Folder 1-7)
    - Exhibits and memoranda, 1857; 39750 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Contradictions of Augusta Cunningham, 1857; 39751 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Miscellaneous notes, undated; 39752 (Box 50, Folder 3-4)
  - III. E. Burdell estate case, 1856 - 1873, n.d.; 39753